PROFESSOR: So far, the big ways we have
accelerated our CSP solvers have
been to exploit ordering--
try good variables first, try good
values first; filtering--
rule out elements of the unassigned
domains based on propagation of
constraints; and now we can do
something very different.
We can look at the structure
of the CSP.
Sometimes you look at a CSP that you're
trying to solve, and you see it
has some special graph structure.
And based on that graph structure,
there'll be some technique available
to you that allows you to solve it
in a particularly efficient way.
And we're going to see a couple
examples of that now.
So for example, if your CSP involves
this giant criminal robot network, you
might think you should go after
the guy in the center.
That would be an example of
exploiting structure.
Let's make that concrete.
So here is the constraint graph for the
problem of map coloring Australia.
And an extreme case of problem structure
is when you look at your
constraint graph--
remember, the constraint graph tells you
which variables have constraints,
it doesn't tell you what those are.
We know in this particular case, they're
inequality constraints, but
the constraint graph doesn't
tell you that.
In this particular case, we look at it
and we see that this graph is broken
into two pieces-- there's the mainland,
and then there's this tiny
little CSP of a single
mode for Tasmania.
That's an extreme case of structure
where we have independent subproblems.
Independent subproblems are great,
because you can solve them separately.
Divide and conquer.
How do we tell when we have
independent subproblems?
You can tell you have independent
subproblems when you look at your
constraint graph, you can do a connected
component analysis of it--
for example, start at some
node and do search--
and when you have multiple connected
components, then they can be solved
independently.
Now, why is this so great?
So here's the good part.
The good part is that if you had n
variables, but you could break it into
a bunch of subproblems with
c variables each.
So n is a big number, but c is small.
You have a bunch of little problems.
Well, then the worst case
solution is much better.
So in particular, you've got a bunch
of problems of size c, and if the
domain size is d, then d to
the c is the expense of
solving each one, right?
And how many of them do you have?
Well, you have n divided by c of them.
So it's now linear in n.
As the problem grows and grows and
grows, you just get more of these
little things, and then
you all get solved
independently, and that's great.
And that's a whole lot better, for
example, than the original case, where
it would have been d to the
n for the whole CSP.
So let's do some back of the envelope.
Let's imagine that n were 80, which
is not that big for a CSP.
d is 2, so all of the domains
are binary-- true/false, or
something like that.
And we can break it up into problems
of size 20, so we get four
problems of size 20.
Well, if we had to solve the whole
thing by enumerating all of the
possible configurations, than we'd
have 2 to the 80 configurations.
If you can do 10 million a second, then
that'll take four billion years,
which is probably an unacceptable
run time.
If instead, you only have to solve four
things, each of which is 2 to the
20th, well, now it's 0.4 seconds,
which sounds a whole lot better.
So there you go.
Galactic time scales, or seconds.
That's the difference when you
have independent subproblems.
So independent subproblems are great.
What's the problem with independent
subproblems?
There are no independent subproblems.
You're never going to look at your
constraint graph and say,
oh, isn't this nice?
I have five different subproblems
that don't interact.
Typically, the problem you set out to
solve is a whole connected thing, and
imposing the problem, you've kind of
already separated off whatever the
separate subproblems are before
you even formulate it.
So this is rare to actually
see separate subproblems.
OK, so let's see if we can come up
with some methods that are more
broadly applicable.